# **Justin Ervin**

Software Engineer / Manager

#### **Personal Info**

**Phone** 

256-473-5751

E-mail

justinaervin@gmail.com

Website

https://justinaervin.github.io/

# **Development Skills**

Python

**SQL** 

**JavaScript** 

C#

.Net

HTML & CSS

Design & Visualization

**Data Analytics** 

# **Key Skills**

Relationship Driven

Self-motivated

Critical Thinker

Encourager

Philomath

Dedicated software engineer and manager with 8+ years of full stack experience developing mission critical systems for a fast growing aerospace company. Automated and optimized numerous processes that eliminated bottlenecks while significantly increasing throughput and decreasing human errors. Lead team responsible for system modernization that garnered corporate wide distinction. Strives on challenges, curve-ball projects, ensuring the follow through, and the prospect of a happy end user.

## **Experience**

# 2015-05 -

present

#### IT Manager/Lead Software Engineer

Aerospace Coatings International

- Lead Software Engineer responsible for developing mission critical systems in multi-code environments.
- Reversed engineered legacy ERP inventory systems to reduce processing time by 65% and provide robust reporting tools
- Built form automation system that either reduced or eliminated physical paperwork while decreasing errors
- Headed team tasked with modernizing back-end infrastructure
- Led DevOps including VM management
- Established & executed plans for long term & day to day managerial operations.

## 2013-05 -

#### **Software Engineer**

2015-05

Aerospace Coatings International

- Designed & developed paid time off management system that led to a 95% reduction physical paper usage
- Designed & developed chemical inventory and tracking system that fully meet regulatory requirements and provided robust reporting options
- Invented drag and drop visual job assignment tool that reduced job assignment time requirements by 40%
- Established automated processes for requesting information from customer that reduced human processing and customer wait time

#### 2010-01 -

#### IT Internship - Web Developer/Technician

2013-05

Aerospace Coatings International

- Designed & built IT asset inventory and assignment system
- Spearheaded bug fix team that improved end user confidence
- Maintained server and network infrastructure to beat required 99.99% up-time
- Strengthened relationship with end users and IT with "Here when you need us" program

#### **Education**

#### 2015-09 -

#### **Master of Science in Data Science - Indiana University**

2017-08

- Courses in: Machine Learning, Distributed Computing, Cloud Computing, Information Visualization
- 3.77 GPA

#### 2008-09 -2013-05

# **Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems - Jacksonville State University**

- Courses in: Software Engineering, Database, Programming, Operating Systems, Networking, Web Services
- Minor: Business Administration
- 3.5 GPA Cum laude
- Omicron Delta Kappa, Upsilon Pi Epsilon